Profile

Yiting Liu is an award-winning XR Lead Developer & Technology Strategist. A multi-disciplinary creative technologist working across all industry verticals with leading Fortune 500 clients such as Accenture, CitiBank, ESPN, Comcast (NBCUniversal Studios), Disney, Credit Agricole and others, she reinvents the future of immersive experiences.

Skills

Development: C#, HTML/CSS/JavaScript, p5.js, three.js, Node.js, Express, Heroku, MongoDB, DigitalOcean, GitHub **Software:** Unity, Unreal, Max/MSP, Spark AR, Lens Studio, Effect House, Cinema 4D, Blender, Adobe Creative Suite, Ableton Live

Professional Experience

Sia Partners | Developer Manager, 2023 - Present

New York, NY

- Spearheading the global spatial computing team of 13, leading large-scale immersive XR deployments
- Revitalized a faltering project in a month, delivering a superior VR application surpassing stakeholder expectations.
- Directing the integration of cutting-edge tools, ensuring scalability and cross-platform compatibility for future growth.
- Mentoring two developers, ensuring seamless knowledge transfer and project continuity.
- Enhanced team productivity by 50% by implementing daily progress reports and task outlines.
- · Technology: OpenXR, OpenAl, AR, VR, Hand/Eye Tracking

Future Colossal | Creative Technologist, 2021 - 2023

New York, NY

- Creative lead for interactive experiences for Fortune 500 clients with large-scale deployment (2,000+ people daily)
- Product lead using cutting edge technology that attracted 90,000 attendees within the first four months
- Specialized in risk assessment, meticulous documentation for software development and conducting post-mortem analyses to optimize project outcomes and inform future strategies.
- Engineered and deployed immersive technical systems for interactive installations, enriching experiences across diverse sectors including theme parks, live entertainment, corporate activations, finance, and sports
- Technology: Computer Vision, ML/AI, AR, UDP/OSC, Projection Mapping and DMX.

NYU ITP | Coding Lab Manager, 2020 - 2021

New York, NY

- Expertly diagnosed and resolved technical challenges across creative coding, physical computing, interaction design, and VR/AR development in 136 remote sessions, showcasing versatility and problem-solving acumen.
- Demystified complex programming concepts in logic, data structures, and algorithm design for over 40 students, enhancing their coding proficiency and analytical thinking.
- Organized and led three state-of-the-art online workshops at ITP Camp, covering Unity, Spark AR, and time management, positioning myself as a thought leader in digital innovation and productivity strategies.

Resilience 2032 | AR Developer, 2020

New York, NY

- Digital storytelling using four dynamic AR filters, revolutionizing the social media theater experience to drive voter awareness for the 2020 elections
- Pioneered innovative creative strategies, amplifying outreach and generating over 4,200 impressions for the Resilience 2032 campaign of the first month

Education

New York University

Master of Professional Studies, Major: Interactive Telecommunications Program

University of Wisconsin-Madison

Bachelor of Business Administration & Bachelor of Arts, Majors: Marketing, Film Production, Minor: Digital Studies

Awards & Special Projects

- MIT XR Hackathon Grand Prize Winner
- ComplexityJam Cash Award for Development
- Adobe Creative Jam People's Choice Award & Runner Up for the Judges' Award
- XR Brain Jam for Games for Change 2022 & Publicized by Unity
- Bucolic Terrains for Microsoft's Spirit of Being